Hello! In today's video you will learn how
it was possible to steal all your cookies
and even more from mobile Firefox browser. The
vulnerability was very creative and involved
multiple steps. It was found and reported by
Pedro Oliveira and he got $5,000 for it. Links
to the blogpost and his profile as always
are in the description. Enjoy the video!
When looking for mobile vulnerabilities with big
impact, one of things you need to check is how the
application uses custom URIs. On android, there
are URIs with content:// protocol. They allow
reading one application's file or data from the
other one. An example of such URI looks like this:
The first part is called content provider and
it indicates what application will be used
to handle this URI. In this case, it will be
mobile Firefox browser. And the second part
is the path of a file that will be opened. And
as you saw on the example, mobile Firefox browser
allowed reading local files using those
content URIs. But after opening such address,
Firefox copied contents of this file into a
temporary location and redirected user into this
location, but not with the content:// protocol but
with a file:// protocol. It's simply used to read
local files. And what's important, the name of the
file in the temporary location remained unchanged.
When defining those content URIs, the application
can specify directories that a user can open.
But Firefox used the following configuration.
It means that the user can read any
file that Firefox has access to.
And among other configuration files inside Firefox
directory, there is one that will be especially
interesting for the attacker. It's cookies.sqlite
which contains all cookies for a specific profile.
Stealing those files would allow the attacker
to take over all the accounts to which he or she
is currently logged in. But first, the attacker
would have to read profiles.ini file which would
reveal the locations of cookie databases.
So our goal will be stealing those files
and the most likely attack scenario will be
that the victim visits our malicious website
that contains the exploit. It's easily possible
to create a website that opens a local file
and iframes its content but still the parent
website has no access to those information.
It's because Same-Origin-Policy would block
such attempts. It's a browser security mechanism
that protects the websites from different
domains to steal each other's data.
In general, websites need to share the same domain
in order to be able to access each other's data.
But the question is how do sites with file://
protocol obey Same-Origin-Policy because they
do not have any domains. Turns out browsers are
very strict about this and it's really hard to
read others file contents. But i'd like to
point out the obvious fact that a file can
access its own contents. Or being more precise,
contents of a file stored under the same path.
And the browser wouldn't notice if under the
same path would be a completely different file.
And coming back to Firefox, all files are being
copied into the same directory and their names are
not being changed, so it's possible to have two
files in different directories but with the same
name and once they are copied into the contentIri
directory, the file will be overwritten.
And that simple idea was worth $5,000 here. Let's
see how the attack workedand explain the exploit.
So we create awebsite and we
assume that a victim visits it.
This is its source code. Our goal at the
moment is stealing the profiles.ini file
from Firefox directory. The iframe will be
executed first. It will download our file
with the name profiles.ini onto the SD card. We'll
take a look at contents of this file in a second.
Then, android intent is being used and
without getting into details, it's the same
as we would use this content:// URI but
with additionally stated html content type.
It would tell the browser to execute contents
of this file even though it has .ini extension.
This will lead into Firefox trying to open
our downloaded file with a content:// URI.
And as you already know, first, Firefox will copy
this file into contentUri directory and it will be
opened in the browser using file:// protocol.
Let's now see its contents. First we open an
iframe with content:// URI which points to the
actual profiles.ini file that we want to steal.
Then, Firefox copies this file into contentUri
directory, overwriting our profiles.ini file
but the old version is still being opened in the
browser. Then, using javascript, we send a request
to window.location. It's a property that contains
information about the current address. So it looks
like the file would just get its own contents
which is of course allowed by Same-Origin-Policy
but at the moment of this request, the file is
no longer the same because it was overwritten.
So we can access contents of this file and
easily send it to our server, achieving
our goal of stealing the profiles.ini file. It
would reveal the locations of cookie databases and
we could steal those files exactly the same way.
The whole process could be automated so that the
exploit does not require any more user interaction
than visiting the website. As mentioned before,
the researcher was awarded $5,000 for this
vulnerability. It was fixed shortly after
being reported to the program and this exploit no
longer works. I think the way the vulnerability
was exploited was really creative and oddly
satisfying to me. If you feel like you've learned
something from this video, leave a like and leave
a subscription. Thanks for watching and goodbye!